# Mikkel Langgaard

## Lauritzen

mikkel.lauritzen@nbi.ku.dk

 $\bullet$  +45 20 69 82 68





## Curriculum Vitae

#### Personal Profile

I am a Ph.D. student in ice flow modeling at the Niels Bohr Institute, University of Copenhagen deeply invested in understanding the dynamics of glaciers and ice sheets and their interplay with the atmosphere. I have experience with teaching and I enjoy discussing physics in a positive and collaborative work environment.

### Education

2019–2021	MSc in physics, University of Copenhagen, Thesis: Fermionic Duality for Integrable Super Spin Chains supervised by Charlotte Fløe Kristjansen
2016-2019	<b>BSc in physics</b> , University of Copenhagen, Thesis: <i>Effective Field Theory for QCD - at Non-zero Lattice Spacing</i> in collaboration with Benjamin Søgaard, supervised by Kim Splittorff
2018	Exchange student, University of British Columbia, Vancouver
2012–2015	High school, Roskilde Katedralskole, SRP: Ellipses and Planetary Motion

## Selected Experience

2019-2021	Taught exer	<b>Teaching Assistant</b> , University of Copenhagen Taught exercise classes, grading homework, going over problems together with the students and helping them out in the laboratory. Courses taught:		
	2022-2023	Electrodynamics 2		
	2022	Mathematics F2 (Complex analysis)		
	2021-2022	Electrodynamics 2		
	2020-2021	Introduction to Linear Algebra and Calculus (LinAlys)		
	2020	Catch-up café in LinAlys in coordination with Sune Rasmussen		
	2020	Mathematics F2 (Complex analysis)		
	2019	Electrodynamics 2		
	2019	Electrodynamics 1		

2018 Private Teacher, Mentordanmark

Helped high school students with mathematics and preparing them for exams.

2015-2016 Ski Representative, Thinggaard Rejser, Zell am See

Guided ski tours, organized events, and provided customer service.

## **Publications**

2021 M. Kieburg, M. Lauritzen, B. T. Søgaard, and K. Splittorff, "New term in

effective field theory at fixed topology", Phys. Rev. D 103, 014501 (2021)

A. Fichtner, C. Hofstede, B. L. N. Kennett, N. F. Nymand, et al., "Fiber-

Optic Airplane Seismology on the Northeast Greenland Ice Stream", The

Seismic Record 3, 125–133 (2023)

2023 M. Lauritzen, G. Aðalgeirsdóttir, N. Rathmann, A. Grinsted, et al., "The

influence of inter-annual temperature variability on the Greenland Ice Sheet

volume", Annals of Glaciology, 1–8 (2023)

#### Volunteer Work

2017, 2019, 2020 Tutor for the new bachelor and master students, organized cabin trips,

campus tours, and helped the new students feel welcome at NBI.

2017–2019 Participated in Fysik Revy $^{\text{TM}}$ , the annual physics cabaret at NBI.

2017, 2019 Helped organize the annual physics galla at NBI, Kæmpefest.

## Computer Skills

Programming Proficient in Python and Matlab with applications in data processing, simula-

tions, machine learning, visualizations, and large-scale data-analysis. Solved

more than 80 problems in Project Euler using Python.

Other Well versed in LaTeX, Linux, Mathematica, Google Colab, and SQL. Some

experience with HTML, PHP and CSS.

#### Miscellaneous

Interests Apart from physics, maths and programming my interests are nature, hiking,

skiing, cooking, technology, and football.

Languages I am fluent in Danish and English, and speak a little French.

Copenhagen, August 21, 2023